I am reading this week's blog post I
will post the link to both the article
I'm referring to as well as my article
that I am reading risk why we won't fail
tech companies have a high risk
associated with them working together
with transparency and democracy
minimizes or eliminates most of the risk
the traditional startups face most of
the risk in our current economy occurs
in the separation and therefore informed
guessing between the creator and the
user most of our true risk exists most
of our true risk exists in the first
project and we have less risk as we
progress and gain members I looked up
what risk a startup faces and I found
this article 14 startup risks
entrepreneurs should consider when
launching their startup I will go
through each of the points and explain
how a company owned by all of us and
operated with transparency and democracy
minimizes or eliminates almost all of
them number one capability risk the risk
that the startup is unable to scale its
capability on a timely basis and it
levels required we are designing every
project with scalability in mind our
members are financially and emotionally
invested in our success and will work
with us as we increase capability when
we are less than optimal we are holding
back our scalability to remain
functional as we systematically grow
when we manage to effectively work with
the starti number ten thousand to a
million then we double by allowing
everyone to invite one person if the
starti number itself is too large we ask
the larger membership for solutions and
create those solutions first to design
risk the risk that the product or
service design does not meet the
required performance standards we're
designing the apps for the request of
our membership if it does not work we
have systems in place to hear why it's
not working and get it to work allowing
issues to be brought up by any user
means we all get a better product with
higher standards again members are
emotionally invested and will bring up
their honest feedback to improve the
product for all users three
developmental risk the risk that
development of the product or service is
not completed on time within budget or
to the defined specifications this is a
risk but men
by our structure and transparency we
have a $250,000 budget for our first
project that is lower that is our budget
is lower than that so we have a large
contingency fund if we do go over budget
the entire membership can offer
solutions and cost-saving strategies or
we can fund raise more money together I
have everyone put in a bit more money or
recruit more members of the original
investment of $25 for economic risk the
risk that the companies success is
sensitive to external economic factors
we are creating a whole new system that
does not rely on our current existing
market forces but currently we need to
be aware of the economic factors that
directly impact us and if there is a
problem we need to see it quickly deal
with it and learns that it is less
likely to happen in the future many eyes
and brains that are involved in care
about our success can foresee problems
and brainstorm solutions in a much more
agile way five economic life risk the
risk that the product or service is
useful life in the marketplace is
shorter than originally anticipated or
projected we are constantly improving
our projects since we are the developer
and the user we listen to our membership
and create new ideas constantly and
improve old ideas so there is always
improvement in response to the members
requests and suggestions some projects
may outlive their usefulness but the
data and function can be saved and put
into newer versions six funding risk the
risk that funding will not be available
at a level or timing required for the
startup to succeed for the first few
projects we are crowdfunding and not
making it within budget or time frame is
addressed above in point three the
funding model is eventually like Netflix
where people pay $10 a month and get
access to our catalog of apps we are
listening to our membership and
designing tools that have the most
positive impact on their lives there
will be little attrition and we can
budget for our numbers to grow or remain
the same we have we have steady income
to budget from the risk is minimized
this risk is minimized but not
eliminated seven legislative and policy
risk aka regulatory risk the risk that
legislative and policy changes will
result in higher costs too
startup transparency and crowdsourcing
are our greatest assets in this risk in
the beginning the laws could be changed
to stop us
before we have enough membership or our
name known so that people care and can
work together to stop it with so many
people able to see where existing where
laws restrict us new and existing we can
work as a large base to make sure we are
in compliance and change the laws that
are unjust when we lobby we do so with
complete transparency and involvement of
our member base 8 maintenance risk the
risk that maintaining the company's
assets at appropriate levels will cost
more than anticipated we have a much
lower maintenance cost than a single
startup as we have economies of scale if
it costs more than we anticipated to
maintain our current apps we can vote
for solutions ie
get more members higher subscription fee
only make income generating ones in an
income generating projects for the next
few projects or just maintain our
current ones again having the membership
as owners and operators means that
solutions can and will come from
anywhere 9 management risk the risk that
management team lacks the skillset and
experience to execute the startups
business plan we are using democracy and
transparency to offset this risk the
Board of Directors is the closest thing
to management and they are operated in
full view of the members that empower
them we all fail or succeed together
anyone can offer management level
suggestions as they have full access to
all the information if the methods we
are using are not working to move us
forward we troubleshoot that 10
operation risks the risk that operating
costs are greater than budgeted or that
the service cannot be provided at the
projected costs we are designing - we
are designed to have minimal operational
costs we reduce redundancy of
departments where possible ie one legal
team and HR team for dozens of projects
not one each
we utilize volunteer label of labour of
crowdsourcing whenever possible and we
create the platforms to help members
find the jobs they want to do for free
our finances are completely transparent
so that any member can suggest ways to
bring down our costs
or bring in more revenue again our
membership our direct owners and if we
go out of business they lose all the
tools we have co-created we will always
vote to maintain the company with people
who do not want the changes needed
leaving 11 procurement risk the risk
relating to the ability of the start-up
to procure quantities and price unit
required scarce resources we are
starting as a tech company and there are
a few scarce resource and there are few
scarce resources involved labour is one
scarce resource and we have a different
incentive than the tech giant's to
recruit with people who want to work for
the greater good whilst having their
needs and most of their wants met will
choose us over the tech giants to work
for those that hold salary above all
else will work for the tech giants we
get the workers who are dedicated to our
mission the other scarce resource we are
dealing with is phone real estate of our
members all apps have to compete to have
their space in the lives of their
customers our apps will be designed to
work in unison so that less real estate
is needed dozens of features in one app
takes up less space than dozens of apps
by themselves we are creating the tools
to deal with scarcity in real life for
our members we create tools to give our
members access to food shelter resources
etc for less and less time and money
when we move into in real life solutions
ie buying up the means of production etc
we have the data to minimize this risk
but it still exists on a much fairer
scale of an undercurrent capitalism we
work together to find internal solutions
to our scarce resources are best
utilized twelve research risk the risk
that the quality of initial research
upon which key company assumptions were
based was flawed in an impactful way we
are not researching to see how we can
create something to profit from the
hypothetical masses we are create we are
asking our membership directly what they
need if this research is wrong then the
membership themselves did not know what
they wanted this is a real risk that we
are constantly looking for so we can
correct for him example the members say
they want a platform that helps them
share food but then it is too complex
for most users so we make a simpler
version for those that require it
thirteen technology risk the risk that
less than optimal technology is
developed or utilized or the
editor leapfrogs the startups technology
this is my favorite one
the only way we truly fail is if
everyone gives up or if someone else
does what we are doing faster and better
if they do that we join them if someone
else happens to create a transparent
democratic trans and technology company
we all own together before we do then we
don't have to we are doing what the
for-profit tech companies cannot do and
they are not our competition any
competition must also be owned by the
people and be open to everyone we are
the people and we can join them to 14
volume demand risk the risk that actual
markets demand for the product or
service will not yield projected sales
volumes this is a real risk that we
account for in the beginning we do not
make our first project or any subsequent
project unless a minimum threshold of
users member / members is already
interested we are not hoping that 10,000
people will want to put in $25 each we
are waiting until they do to start the
first project we are creating in direct
relation to demand and supply in what
they want because we are not doing
because we are doing it together there
is no failure we are constantly seeking
out ways to improve our lives and the
company improve our lives and the
company that gives us those tools the
exact structure of every aspect may
change as what we thought would work
needs to be tweaked we create a dynamic
system that responds to the needs of our
members ie
all the people of Earth who want to by
allowing anyone to voice opposition or
risk as they see them
we encourage dissent we do not suppress
it every mistake is learning and helps
us improve as individuals as well as
improve the system itself thank you
please like and subscribe so we can
change the world together with our own
technology company